Darshan Bhanushali

Jersey City, NJ 07307, USA | +15513447214 | dwarsh.b@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/dwarshb | developerspace.medium.com

SUMMARY

Experienced Software Engineer with more than 5 years of experience developing mobile and web applications. Proficient in Kotlin and Android development principles, and have implemented features improving user engagement and application efficiency. Successfully led cross-disciplinary projects, integrating payment gateways and APIs that increased revenue.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Soopra AI | San Francisco, CA

Software Engineer, Android

Dec 2023 - Present

- Crafting multi-platform applications using Compose Multiplatform for seamless interaction with AI personas, facilitating user-creator dialogue.
- Conducted code reviews and contributed to debugging sessions.
- Utilized Android Jetpack's LiveData for efficient data updates, enhancing user experience and responsiveness.
- Employed MVVM architecture and Dagger for dependency injection to create scalable applications.
- Implemented and maintained CI/CD pipelines, ensuring smooth and efficient deployment processes.

Inscripts Pvt Ltd | Mumbai, India

Software Developer, Android

Aug 2019 - Jul 2022

- Engineered reusable UI kits and a chat-widget for <u>CometChat</u> that is being utilized by 10,000+ developers and clients.
- Led integration of new payment gateway, reduces transaction processing time by 20%, increases client satisfaction by 40%.
- Participated in investigations when hitting the limits of scale, contributing to the stability and scalability of applications.
- Collaborated with 25-member team to deliver end-to-end solutions for client projects, utilizing **Agile methodologies**.
- Drove a 30% revenue increase by integrating video calling features, utilizing Kotlin and Android SDKs.
- Integrated Firebase, APIs, Geo Location, and VoIP Services, resulting in a remarkable 50% boost in productivity.
- Implemented Android Automation using Expresso, Robotium and UI Automator and wrote integration test cases.

Heer Properties | Mumbai, India

Software Developer, Web

Jun 2017 - Jul 2019

- Crafted dynamic web applications with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, meeting industry standards for speed and scalability.
- Slashed page loading time by 18% and amplified search engine indexing by 8.6x, leading to a 200% surge in website traffic.
- Leveraged Google Analytics to manage and optimize events, resulting in a 33% increase in leads for the customer support.

CKILLO

Programming Language: Java, Kotlin, C++, SQL, Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP.

Development Skills: Android Development, Web Development, API Development, Software Development Fundamentals **Data Analysis:** Data Cleaning, Data Visualization, Statistical Analysis, Python Libraries (Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn) **Tools:** Android Studio, Google Play Publication, Firebase, Git, JIRA, Adobe Photoshop, Figma, Docker, Jupyter Notebook

EDUCATION

Stevens Institute of Technology Master of Science in Software Engineering	Sep 2022 – Dec 2023
 University of Mumbai Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering. 	Aug 2016 – Jun 2019
 Maharashtra State Board of Technical Education Diploma in Computer Engineering. 	Aug 2013 – May 2016

PROJECTS

PROJECTS					
University Of Mumbai <u>Heart Disease Prediction System</u>	Jun 2018 - Feb 2019				
Created a sophisticated HDPS, leveraging Machine Learning techniques and Flask in Python					
• Stevens Institute Of Technology ShiftDay	Oct 2022 - Dec 2022				
An Android Application that allows manager and employee to schedule the work shifts.					
• Stevens Institute Of Technology Fitness Connect	Oct 2023 - Dec 2023				
A Dot Net-based web application, offering a comprehensive fitness tracking and social platform.					

CERTIFICATIONS

 Certificate for Com 	pletion of Jav	a Training	(1885589Q0R))	STP, IIT Bombay
---	----------------	------------	--------------	---	-----------------

Feb 2017

Certificate for Completion of Python Training (1202095A5C) | STP. IIT Bombay

Aug 2017

Certificate for Completion of Java Business Application Training (1202095X2G) | STP, IIT Bombay

Aug 2018